## Andrej Suvoraŭ

+375 29 304 19 99 / suvri4@gmail.com / https://github.com/suVrik

### Summary

I have extensive experience in game engine architecture, networking, rendering, multithreading, and gameplay programming. I actively participated in competitive programming contests for several years and have strong knowledge of algorithms and data structures. My education in applied mathematics gave me a deep insight into linear algebra and calculus. I started my professional game development career at Wargaming, the most renowned game development studio in Belarus. Shortly thereafter, my team formed a new studio where we created a cutting-edge game engine from scratch and a AAA mobile game to utilize it.

I've been making games since I was 10 years old and developed over a dozen small games in different genres and art styles, targeting various platforms. I was always fascinated by PC and console games, that's why in 2021 I decided to pursue my goal of working in this area.

# Experience

### Independent Game Developer February 2021 – August 2021

Made a game engine tech demo to gain a proficient understanding of common rendering techniques. It uses a simple yet efficient rendering API to abstract away from modern graphics APIs such as Vulkan and DirectX 12; a frame graph architecture to manage render passes and attachments; a job system to take advantage of all available processing power; and it includes many of the common rendering techniques such as frustum culling, texture streaming, skeletal animation, particle effects, physically based rendering, image-based lighting, percentage-closer soft shadows, translucent shadows, bloom and more. The source code and a showreel are available on my GitHub profile.

#### Gameplay Engineer at Press Fire Games May 2018 – February 2021

Involved in the full-cycle production of a multiplayer AAA title. Contributed to development of Blitz Engine and its tools. Worked on performance, memory and network optimizations. Developed a large number of gameplay mechanics for the mobile shooter <u>Battle Prime</u>. Developed a prototype of another unreleased title. Many of my ideas impacted the fundamental development concepts.

#### Game Engine Developer at Wargaming March 2018 – May 2018

Assisted in developing and bug-fixing of <u>World of Tanks: Blitz</u> game engine. Prototyped gameplay mechanics for an unannounced project.

## Freelance Game Developer June 2013 – March 2018

Designed and developed browser, mobile, and PC games, created educational games for Vretta.com.

### Front-End Engineer at Akavita November 2012 – June 2013

Web development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

#### Education

Belarusian State University, Faculty of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, 2018. Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics.

#### **Awards**

3rd place Ludum Dare 34 Worldwide, 1st place Ludum Dare 34 Minsk, 2nd place Global Game Jam 2015 Minsk, 3rd place Ludum Dare 33 Minsk, over 300,000 views on <u>newgrounds.com</u>.